## ROBBIE KIRKBRIDE | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

London, UK | +447788930837 | robbie.w.m.kirkbride@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Developer seeking a new challenge having spent five years in Civil Engineering. I am extremely enthusiastic about tech, driven by my desire to keep learning and to use my skills to make a positive impact on the world. I am a language agnostic coder who is proactive, with the ability to pick up new skills and technologies at pace.

	CORE COMPETENCIES
Languages	TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Pytho
Libraries/frameworks	React, Node.JS, Express.JS, Tailwind, Jest, Cypre
Architecture	MCV, Microservices, REST, SPA
Tools	MongoDB, PostgresSQL, GitHub, JWT, Postman,
	EVERIENCE

## **EXPERIENCE**

Makers Academy - October 2022 to February 2023

Ecoliday - MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, JWT, Tailwind, Jest, Cypress (GitHuB)

- Eco-conscious travel planner created during my two week Makers final project in a five person Agile team with regular stand-ups, retros and daily pair programming.
- Built with the MERN stack in four 2-day sprints using GitHub for Version Control. We
  incrementally improved the MVP each sprint, developing a consistently usable product.
- Created a REST API that called three third party APIs (climatiq, geoapify, google maps), with a total of eight calls made per search.

Frontleft - TypeScript, MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, JWT, CSS, Jest, Cypress (GitHub)

- A mobile-first festival planner app created with TypeScript.
- Built from the ground up with the MERN stack, implementing JWT authentication, Bcrypt password encryption, Sendgrid email notifications and file uploads with Multer/Sharp.

**COWI UK** - Engineering Consultant - January 2018 to October 2022

- Project manager responsible for collaborating with stakeholders, managing client expectations, monitoring programmes and carrying out quality assurance processes.
- Developed in-house design software tools in VBA, using Git for version control.
- Used Python to analyse Point Cloud Survey datasets of structures to offer savings to clients.
- Processed topographical data using MATLAB to streamline design calculations.
- Co-founded an interoffice network that organised conferences, technical and social events.
- Delivered the design of a 300m tall mast with 33% less CO2e than the initial proposal, with additional cost and programme savings, despite working under intense time pressure.
- Created FEA models and led the fatigue analysis of the Mumbai Trans Harbour Link design.

## **EDUCATION**

Makers Academy - Coding Bootcamp - October 2022 to February 2023

- Focus on language-agnostic development by building strong self-directed study skills
- Fostered coding best-practices such as test-driven development, SOLID principles, version control and agile methodologies.
- Excelled due to my strong analytical thinking and systematic approach, both in planning and production, establishing watertight TDD processes and debugging techniques.
- Communicated complex content methodically and concisely, for example explaining how a class system could be broken down to adhere to the Single Responsibility Principle.
- Signed up to the mentoring scheme, a supervisory trait carried forward from COWI.

University of Bristol - Civil Engineering, MEng (First Class) - 2013 to 2017